thetiebar.com 2019-05-21

# The Tie Bar - Privacy Policy

### Who We Are

This Privacy Policy describes how The Tie Bar Operating Company, LLC, along with its representatives, officers, shareholders, subsidiaries, affiliates, parents, employees, and agents (collectively "The Tie Bar" or "we" or "us" or "our"), uses and collects your personal information (defined below) on thetiebar.com (our "website") and elsewhere. We may amend or change this Privacy Policy from time to time. Changes to the Privacy Policy will be posted to our website. 

You may contact us regarding this policy by emailing [privacy@thetiebar.com](mailto:privacy@thetiebar.com) or through the mail: The Tie Bar, attn: Privacy, 224 N Desplaines St #200, Chicago, IL 60661. 

### Who You Are

We collect personal information from a few different types of people:

  * Customers of the Tie Bar who come to our website to purchase goods.
  * Visitors to The Tie Bar website who may or may not choose to purchase goods from our website.
  * Service Providers and third parties who perform functions for us.
  * Personnel who are our employees and contractors.

If you are a service provider or personnel, how we handle your personal information is set forth in our agreement with you or our employee policies, respectively.

### Information We Collect

To provide you with services, including access to our website, we need to collect and process some information about you (your "personal information").

We collect and retrieve your personal information in a number of different ways. Why we collect your information and what we do with it depends on the type of information. The tables below provide more details.

#### Your Name and Contact Details

If you create an account or place an order with us, we collect your name and contact details, such as your email address, shipping addresses, and phone number.

Name | 

  * For shipment or billing details
  * To personalize your contact or website experiences
  * To prevent and detect fraud against either you or The Tie Bar

---|---  
Email | 

  * To send updates about your order
  * To contact you regarding issues around your order
  * To update you on items in your cart
  * To keep you up to date about The Tie Bar products and promotions. We will only send you these emails with your permission, and you can unsubscribe at any time – just use the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of any The Tie Bar email
  * To prevent and detect fraud against either you or The Tie Bar
  * To help us identify new customers

Phone Number | 

  * To contact you for urgent issues surrounding your order
  * To prevent and detect fraud against either you or The Tie Bar
  * To support you as a customer when requested

Shipping Address | 

  * To complete the shipment of your order
  * To prevent and detect fraud against either you or The Tie Bar
  * To allow us to understand and improve the experience for users like you

#### Your Date of Birth Information

Birthday | 

  * To prevent and detect fraud against either you or The Tie Bar
  * To send a birthday gift, if you are subscribed to our promotional emails

---|---  
Birth Year | 

  * To improve and personalize your shopping experience

We are committed to protecting the privacy of children. The Tie Bar website is not designed for or directed to children under the age of 16. We do not collect personal information from any person we actually know is under the age of 16.

#### Your Payment Information

When you place an order, we require payment information on file. When you enter your payment information (credit card number, expiration date, and CVV code) it is sent directly to a secure third-party credit card processing center. The Tie Bar does not store any direct credit card or 3rd party payment information. We do store billing addresses, generic payment type, and, if you opt in, the last four digits of your credit card for your convenience during the ordering process.

Billing Address | 

  * Our payment partners require this information to process an order
  * To prevent and detect fraud against either you or The Tie Bar

---|---  
Generic Payment Type | 

  * To give reference for support issues
  * To alert you when we detect or are verifying fraudulent activity
  * To allow us to understand and improve the experience for users like you

Last Four Digits of Credit Card | 

  * To provide convenience for you when you choose to order again

#### Your Contact History With Us

What you've said to us — for example, over the phone, on email, or on live chat.

Email Correspondence | 

  * To respond to your requests to make sure you receive great customer service and ensure that any and all concerns or issues have been addressed
  * For a historic record of your contacts to save time during your inquiries
  * To ensure issues and questions you raised are proactively addressed for other customers
  * To train our staff to ensure the best experience possible for all customers who contact us

---|---  
Phone Correspondence | 

  * To respond to your requests to make sure you receive great customer service and ensure that any and all concerns or issues have been addressed
  * To train our staff to ensure the best experience possible for all customers who contact us

Live Chat Logs | 

  * To respond to your requests to make sure you receive great customer service and ensure that any and all concerns or issues have been addressed
  * For a historic record of your contacts to save time during your inquiries
  * To train our staff to ensure the best experience possible for all customers who contact us

Survey or Site Feedback | 

  * To respond to your requests to make sure you receive great customer service and ensure that any and all concerns or issues have been addressed
  * To improve the experience for you and other users

#### Purchase and Product Feedback History and Saved Products

What you've bought, what's in your shopping cart, and what's on your wishlist.

Purchased Items | 

  * To fulfill and ship your order as requested
  * To allow you to return and review delivered items
  * To tailor your experience around your interests
  * To improve our product selection and experience for you and other users
  * To help our buyers make sure we have the best items in stock for you and other customers
  * To prevent and detect fraud against either you or The Tie Bar

---|---  
Items Added to Your Cart | 

  * To allow your order to be completed smoothly when you're ready to check out
  * To update you on items in your cart, including low quantity or sale status
  * To tailor your experience around your interests

Wishlist Items | 

  * To allow you to save, organize, recall, and share items you've selected
  * To allow us to personalize product recommendations toward your interests

Reviewed Items | 

  * To better inform other customers about the pros and cons of a product
  * To provide feedback on fit based on various physical attributes 

#### Information About Your Device Type, and How You Use Our Website

We automatically receive and record information from your browser or device when you visit our site, including your IP address and device type (i.e. computer, tablet, or smart phone), cookies, and data about which pages you visit. This information is stored in log files and is collected automatically. If you have an account with us, we may combine this information with other personal information we collect about you.

More information about how we use cookies is listed below in the Cookies and Advertising section.

IP Address | 

  * To ensure the security of our website and determine, on an anonymous basis, where our customers are located
  * To prevent and detect fraud against either you or The Tie Bar

---|---  
Device Type and Browser Type | 

  * To improve the experience for you and other users like you
  * To resolve customer issues that center around devices, operating systems, or browsers used
  * To prevent and detect fraud against either you or The Tie Bar and to keep your data secure

Page Visit History | 

  * To improve the experience for you and other users like you
  * To respond to and resolve any customer issues based on a specific page or page type

Identification Cookies | 

  * To provide you with The Tie Bar advertising, including across your devices
  * To provide you with a personalized shopping experience and ensure our advertising is relevant to you

#### Specific Details About You

We collect body information related to fit measurements and photographs for product representations. We collect fit details you provide when placing an order to ensure that we provide you with products in the proper size. You can choose to enter your fit details (height, body type, weight, and measurements) in your profile. There are four ways we might have your photographs: if you post a photo review, if you email us your photo, if you accepted our request to use your photo from a third-party site (like Instagram), or if the photo is provided to us by a third party (such as a wedding photographer). We will never use your photograph without your express permission or when a third party warrants that it has your express permission to share your photograph with us. You may withdraw this consent at any time by emailing us at [privacy@thetiebar.com](mailto:privacy@thetiebar.com) or, in the case where we receive your picture through a third party, by contacting the third party and withdrawing your consent, or by changing your privacy settings on the third party website to prohibit us from being able to access the picture.

With the exception of fit measurements for specific purchases, your provision of this information is completely optional and we will not use this information without your consent. You may withdraw your consent any time by emailing us at [privacy@thetiebar.com](mailto:privacy@thetiebar.com).

Uploaded Photos and Photos from Third Parties | 

  * To help other customers see what our clothing looks like on actual customers
  * To offer other customers the products and shopping experience most relevant to them
  * To showcase styling ideas and product fit from other customers

---|---  
Your Fit Details | 

  * To provide you with products that fit you
  * To help us better suggest products and sizes for you
  * To help our customer service representatives guide you to the correct size

Your Gender | 

  * To help us better suggest products for you

#### Your Public Reviews, Blog Comments, and Social Media Information

We allow our customers to provide public feedback in the form of reviews about our website and comments on our blog posts. Please remember that any information that you disclose on public portions of the website, such as the reviews and blog comments, through any email you send to us for any purpose, or through any social media site that we use are not private and may be viewed (and potentially shared) on our website and elsewhere. Please use caution when deciding to disclose your personal information in the public portions of our website, in an email to us or on social media.

We also allow you to use social media websites to contact us and share your Tie Bar purchases. By doing so, we may collect information from your social media profile. You can control how much of the information you place on social media websites is public by visiting these websites and adjusting your privacy settings.

Site Review | 

  * To improve the experience for you and other users like you
  * To respond to your requests and ensure you receive great customer service

---|---  
Blog Comments | 

  * To provide feedback based on your communications
  * To allow us to reference contest entries

#### Anonymous Aggregated Information

We also receive anonymous and aggregated personal information through data analytics services. We use these analytics to ensure our website functions and to improve the The Tie Bar shopping experience. These analytics services record information such as how often you visit thetiebar.com, what actions you take on our website, aggregated usage, performance data, errors and debugging information, and how you got to our website. We do not link the information from our analytics services to any personal information that you submit to us.

#### Information We Receive from Third Parties

In addition to receiving information directly from you or from data analytics services, we receive some personal information about you from third parties, including social media websites, marketing companies, and third-party cookies. We generally use this information to personalize your shopping experience and to provide you with information about our products.

#### Our Legal Bases For Collecting and Processing Your Information

When you access or use our website, we collect, use, and otherwise process your personal information as described in this policy. We rely on a number of legal bases to use your information:

  * As necessary to perform a contract with you or to take steps in preparation for a contract with you, including enabling you to make a purchase from us;
  * Because you have consented to the processing, such as for receiving marketing messages or third-party data sharing related to advertising;
  * As necessary to comply with a legal obligation, a court order, or to exercise or defend legal claims;
  * As necessary for the purposes of our or a third party's legitimate interests; and
  * As necessary for the vital interests of you or a third party.

Here are some of our legitimate interests for collecting and processing your personal information:

Detecting and preventing fraud: We have a legitimate interest in detecting and preventing fraud. To do so, it is necessary that we collect and retain information about each transaction made at The Tie Bar. The credit card companies and payment processors we work with require some of this information in the event that fraudulent charges are made using your credit card. We also use information about your orders and transactions ourselves for our in-house fraud detection processes.

Providing access to and improving thetiebar.com: We may use your information to improve and customize our website, including sharing of your information for such purposes, and this is necessary to pursue our legitimate interests of improving our website and our products. This is also necessary to enable us to pursue our legitimate interest in understanding how our website is being used, and to develop and expand our customer base. It is also necessary to allow us to pursue our legitimate interest in improving our website's functionality and in obtaining insights into what our customers and potential customers want.

Providing access to and improving our customer service: We may use your information to provide you with customer service, and also to improve the service we provide to all customers. This is necessary for us to pursue our legitimate interest in providing great customer service.

Improving our product offerings: We may use your information to improve the products offered at The Tie Bar, and to inform our buying team so they can provide you and our other customers with a great selection of products. This is necessary for us to pursue our legitimate interest in being your destination for affordable luxury.

Keeping our website and your data secure: We have a legitimate interest in ensuring the security of our website, including enhancing protection of our company and our customers against spam, harassment, intellectual property infringement, crime, and security risks of all kind.

Sharing information about our products: we may use your information to contact you about offers, promotions, and products on The Tie Bar website. You may unsubscribe from these communications at any time.

### Information We Share

Except as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy, we will not provide access to your personal information to third parties for any unauthorized purpose. We never sell or share your contact information to other companies for their direct marketing purposes.

The Tie Bar works closely with third-party businesses (our "vendors") for a variety of purposes, including assisting us to perform and improve our website, to deliver your orders, and to provide advertising and email services. These vendors include payment processors, research companies, marketing providers, and analytics and security providers. These third parties have limited access to your information, and may use your information only to perform these tasks on our behalf. We make sure our vendors have contractually agreed to implement technical and organizational measures that are appropriate under this Privacy Policy.

It is necessary for us to share your information with some of our vendors in order to complete our contract with you; for example, to allow them to process payments and shipments and to help us keep our website secure. Other vendors help us improve our website and our products; for example, by helping us conduct research into how we could better serve our customers, or reach new customers. We have a legitimate interest in working with these vendors to improve our business.

The Tie Bar also may share demographic information about our website visitors with vendors, but it will be aggregated and de-personalized, so personal information is not revealed.

Your information will remain subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy even if we undergo a business transition. However, we may transfer your information to a successor person or entity upon an acquisition or other corporate reorganization. Any party who receives your information as a result of a business transition will be obligated to treat your information according to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

We may also disclose your information if we have a good faith belief that we are required to do so by law or if acting with a good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to: (1) comply with legal process; (2) enforce our Terms of Service; (3) respond to legal claims; (4) respond to your requests for customer service or transaction completion; or (5) protect the rights, property or personal safety of The Tie Bar, the website's users or the public. In these cases, our use of your information may be necessary for the purposes of our or a third party's legitimate interest in keeping our website secure, preventing harm or crime, enforcing or defending legal rights, or preventing damage. Such use may also be necessary to comply with a legal obligation, a court order, or to exercise or defend legal claims. It may also be necessary in the public interest (such as to prevent crime).

### Correcting, Deleting, and Receiving Your Information

Much of your information is stored in your The Tie Bar account profile for as long as your account is active. You may change or correct the information in your account profile by clicking here or emailing [privacy@thetiebar.com](mailto:privacy@thetiebar.com). Only your first and last name and email address are required to have an account with The Tie Bar.

You may unsubscribe from marketing communications from The Tie Bar at any time. To do so, you may click the "unsubscribe" link in each marketing email or email your request to [privacy@thetiebar.com](mailto:privacy@thetiebar.com).

Depending on your location, such as the EEA or Canada, you may also have certain additional rights with respect to your information, such as:

  * data access and portability (including the right to obtain a copy of your personal data, some of which is available through your account profile);
  * data correction (including the ability to update your personal data, much of which you can change directly using your account settings);
  * data deletion (including the right to have The Tie Bar delete your personal information, except information we are required by law to retain);
  * withdrawal of consent (when we rely on your consent to process your information, such as for our marketing emails); and
  * objection to processing (when our processing is based on legitimate interests; this includes, in limited circumstances, the right to ask The Tie Bar to stop processing your personal data).

If you are located in the EEA or Canada and would like a copy of your data, to have your data corrected, to have your data deleted, to withdraw consent to our further processing your information, or to object to our processing based on legitimate interests, please email privacy@thetiebar.com with your request. You may also email our representative in the European Union at thetiebar@gdprrepresentative.eu.

Without prejudice to any other rights you may have, if you are located in the EEA or Canada, you have the right to lodge a complaint with your local data protection regulator.

#### Retention of Your Information

Unless you are located in the EEA or Canada and have exercised one of your rights listed above, The Tie Bar will retain your information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal and financial obligations (for example, to comply with applicable tax/revenue laws, to enforce our agreements, and as otherwise described in this policy). We will generally retain your account information for as long as you have an active account with The Tie Bar. If your account becomes inactive, we will maintain your personal information for as long as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, the obligations of our service providers, and our legitimate business interests. Items placed in your shopping cart will remain there for 30 days.

### Cookies and Advertising

When you visit thetiebar.com we insert some instructions on your computer or mobile device. These instructions will be in the form of a "cookie" or similar file. Cookies are small pieces of instruction stored on your hard drive or device, not on our website. Cookies provide us with information that we use to enhance your experience on thetiebar.com. Right now, there are two basic types of cookies. One is a session cookie which terminates when the user's session ends. The second is a persistent cookie, which is a text file that remains stored on your computer for a period of time. Your Internet browser contains instructions about how to remove or block persistent cookies. If you reject all cookies, you may not be able to create or sign in to your account with us or otherwise take full advantage of the thetiebar.com website.

Cookies we use fall into one of five categories: strictly necessary, analytics, functionality, advertising, and social media . The purposes performed by these cookies are summarized in the table below. You can obtain more information about cookies at <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>. For a full list of the cookies we use on our website, you may contact us at [privacy@thetiebar.com](mailto:privacy@thetiebar.com).

Strictly Necessary Cookies | 

These cookies are essential to make our site work. They enable you to move around the site and use its features. Without these cookies, services that are necessary for you to be able to use our site, such as accessing secure areas, cannot be provided.  
  
---|---  
Analytics Cookies | 

These cookies collect information about how people are using our site, including which pages are visited the most often, how people are moving from one link to another, and if visitors get error messages from certain pages. All information these cookies collect is grouped together with information from other people's use of our site on an anonymous basis. Overall, these cookies provide us with analytical information about how our site is performing and how we can improve it.  
  
Functionality Cookies | 

These cookies allow us to remember choices you make and tailor our site to provide enhanced features and content to you. For example, these cookies can be used to remember your user name, language choice or country selection, changes you've made to text size or font, and other parts of pages that you can customize.  
  
Advertising Cookies | 

These cookies are used to deliver advertisements that are more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as to help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign. This information may be shared with other organizations, such as advertising partners. This means after you have been to our site, you may see some advertisements about our services elsewhere on the internet.  
  
Social Media Cookies | 

In order to enhance your internet experience and make the sharing of content easier, some of the pages on our website may contain tools or applications that are linked to third party social media service providers such as Facebook, Twitter or Google+. Through these tools or applications the social media service provider may set its own cookies on your device. We do not control these cookies and you should check the social media service provider's website for further details about how they use cookies.  
  
We may also use web beacons. A web beacon is an invisible graphic on a web page or email that is programmed to collect non-personally identifiable information about the use of a given website or newsletter, such as whether or not an email is opened and viewed.

We partner with third parties to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third-party partners may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you with advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. These technologies allow a site to recognize your computer or mobile device each time you use thetiebar.com. We rely on your consent to drop and read non-technically necessary cookies. To opt-out from cookies placed by companies that provide online behavioral advertising services, you can opt-out at the following online advertising industry website: The Digital Advertising Alliance Website, <http://www.aboutads.info/>, or the European Digital Advertising Alliance Website, [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

#### Do Not Track Signals

Some browsers have a "do not track" feature that lets you tell websites that you do not want to have your online activities tracked. At this time, we respond to browser "do not track" signals by blocking placement of cookies on your device. Please note that you will not be able to place an order without accepting the following cookies:

  * _ttb_cart_id
  * _ttb_payment_nonce

You may configure acceptance of these cookies in your browser settings.

### Security and Storage

#### How We Protect Your Information

Bar complies with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS). This means that when we collect or transmit sensitive information such as a credit or debit card number, we use industry standard methods to protect that information.

Although we take reasonable measures to safeguard against unauthorized disclosures of your information, no e-commerce platform, website, electronic database or system is completely secure.

#### Where We Are Located

The Tie Bar is located in the United States, and we primarily store your information in the United States. By using our website and/or providing us with information, you are agreeing to transfer and store your data in the United States.

To our international customers: the privacy laws and standards in the United States, including the level of protection applied to your data and the rights of authorities to access your personal information, may differ from those that apply in the country in which you reside. The European Commission has not made a determination that the United States adequately provides safeguards for the transfer of data, and at this time The Tie Bar has not put in place the exact safeguards set forth in GDPR Article 46. The transfer of your data to the United States is necessary for the performance of our contract with you (so we can process your order) and/or to take pre-contractual measures at your request (i.e. to set up your Tie Bar account).

### Third Party Websites

thetiebar.com contains links to other websites. Other websites we link to include social platforms. We also use third-party plug-ins in certain places on our website. For example, when you click on an icon on the The Tie Bar website to share our products on a third party social platform, you are also loading content from that third-party site. That site may request cookies directly from your browser. These interactions are subject to the privacy policy and terms of service of the third-party site, not ours. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such services. We do not make any representations regarding the policies or practices of third parties. When you use third-party sites or services, their own terms and privacy policies will govern your use of those sites or services. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of third parties before disclosing personal information to them. For the purposes of E.U. law, these third parties are independent controllers of data.

### Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of The Tie Bar who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of personally identifiable information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. However, at this time we do not share any of your personally identifiable information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes.

#### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this policy, or if you wish to exercise any rights that you may have in your information, you may contact us at [privacy@thetiebar.com](mailto:privacy@thetiebar.com). If you reside in the EU, our EU representative may be contacted at [thetiebar@gdprrepresentative.eu](mailto:thetiebar@gdprrepresentative.eu).

Last Updated: 30th July 2018
